This story is a work of fiction.
这个故事是虚构的
Or rather, everything in this world is mostly fictional.
或者说 这个世界上的一切都是虚构的
It's made up…
是被编造
and exaggerated.
和夸大的
They hide whatever is an inconvenience.
他们把所有不便隐藏起来
If that's the case, fans of idols would prefer that they made up good lies.
如果是那样的话 粉丝们会更喜欢偶像编造美好的谎言
In this world, lies are a weapon.
在这个世界上 谎言是一种武器
Ai!
爱！
I wish I could've seen this cuteness in person!
真希望我能亲眼看到这么可爱的女孩
Idol group B Komachi's permanent ace and irreplaceable center role,
偶像团体“B小町”的绝对王牌 和不可替代的C位偶像
the ultimate 16-year-old beauty, Ai!
16岁的终极美女 爱
Four years since they formed!
他们已经成立四年了
The group has slowly gained popularity and media coverage,
这个组合慢慢获得了 知名度和媒体的报道
and they've finally caught the public's eye!
他们终于引起了公众的注意
It starts here! This is where her path to stardom…
一切从这里开始 这就是她的明星之路
Why are you in a patient's hospital room, playing an idol's DVD?
你为什么在病房里播放偶像的光盘？
Haven't you got any common sense?
难道你一点常识都没有吗？
Observing beauty is good for your health.
看美女对你的健康有好处
Since no idol concerts are held in the countryside here.
因为这里没有偶像演唱会
It's part of medical practice.
这是医疗实践的一部分
You're recruiting cult followers.
你在招募邪教信徒
Don't make that our hospital's official views.
别把这当成我们医院的官方观点
Oh, speaking of which, Doctor. It trending on Twitter earlier…
说到这个 医生 之前推特上有个热门话题
What?!
什么？
Ai's going on hiatus?!
爱要停止活动了？
So you really are a cult fan.
所以你真的是狂热粉丝啊
Isn't that girl only 16? You lolicon.
那个女孩不是才16岁吗？ 你这个萝莉控
Call me anything but that.
叫我什么都行 就是别叫我萝莉控
There's a reason for it, a good reason.
这是有原因的 一个很合理的原因
I also did my internship at this hospital.
我也在这家医院实习过
Back then, I used to slack off in patients' rooms just like now.
那时候 我也像现在一样在病房里偷懒
Get to work.
回去工作
One of the patients I met at that time changed my destiny.
我当时遇到的一个病人 改变了我的命运
And this is Mei-Mei! Her dancing is good!
这个女孩就是美美 她舞跳得很好
Hm.
是吗？
Ari-pyan and Kyun-pan are better at singing.
阿里比安和京潘唱歌更好听
But my favorite…
但我最喜欢的…
has got to be Ai!
只能是爱！
We're about the same age, but she's so mature and good at singing and dancing!
我们差不多大 但她很成熟 擅长跳舞和唱歌
Above all, I love her face.
最重要的是 我喜欢她的脸
If I could be reborn, I want this face.
如果我能重生 我想要那张脸
What do you mean reborn? Don't say such stupid stuff.
重生是什么意思？ 不要说这种愚蠢的话
You need to dream more, Doctor.
你需要多做梦 医生
Haven't you ever thought, "What if I was born as the child of a celebrity?"
你有没有想过 “如果我是名人的孩子呢？”
What if you had the looks and connections since the time you were born?
你一出生就有那样的长相和人脉？
Nope.
没有
You really don't dream enough.
你真的不爱做梦
Sarina, you're cute too.
纱利奈 你也很可爱
There's no need to be reborn.
没有必要重生
Once you're discharged, go become an idol.
你一出院 就去当偶像吧
Then I'll be your fan.
我就当你的粉丝
Really?
真的吗？
Doctor, I love you! Marry me!
医生 我爱你 跟我结婚吧
Give me a break, that'll be social suicide.
那简直是社会性自杀 饶了我吧
You moralist.
你这个道德家
Too bad. I'll think about it seriously once you become 16.
很遗憾 等你到了16岁 我再认真考虑吧
Sixteen, huh?
16岁吗？
Doctor, you're mean.
医生 你太刻薄了
It's a realistic plan.
这是个现实的计划
Anaplastic astrocytoma.
间变性星形细胞瘤
She was only 12 years old.
她只有12岁
If she were still alive, she'd be 16, just like Ai.
如果她现在还活着 应该16岁了 跟爱一样大
I must be seeing Sarina in the idol that she liked.
我肯定是在纱利奈喜欢的偶像身上 看到了她的影子
I just want to watch over Ai as she walks the path that Sarina dreamed of walking.
我只想看看纱利奈梦寐以求的那条路
I see.
明白了
So basically, you're a lolicon.
所以基本上 你是一个萝莉控
Were you listening? Wasn't that a pretty touching story?!
你在听吗？ 那不是个很感人的故事吗？
Doctor, your obsession with her feels crude.
医生 你对她的痴迷让我觉得很下流
Aren't you using Sarina as an excuse to unleash your desires?
你不是在利用纱利奈 来释放你的欲望吗？
Don't be stupid. I swear on her name, I'm supporting Ai with a pure heart!
别傻了 我以纱利奈之名发誓 我在用一颗纯洁的心 支持着爱
But if that Ai girl asked you out, you would go out with her, wouldn't you?
但如果那个叫“爱”的女孩约你出去 你会跟她出去的 不是吗？
Lunch break's over now. I'm going back to work.
现在 午休时间结束了 回去工作吧
Well, Doctor? Swearing on Sarina's name, what's the answer?
怎么样 医生？以纱利奈之名发誓 答案是什么？
But I'm worried about Ai. I hope she comes back safely.
但我很担心爱 我希望她平安归来
OB-GYN
（妇产科）
Hi, thanks for waiting.
你好 让你久等了
Um, so this is your first visit here, Hoshino.
所以 这是你第一次来这里 星野
Yes.
是的
Based on her belly, she's at about 20 weeks.
从她腹部的情况看 她大概怀孕20周了
Pretty late for a first examination.
才第一次过来检查 实在太晚了
She's 16. I see, so that's why.
她今年16岁 我明白了 这就是原因
One of those ones who came this far, being unable to consult anybody.
那些走到这一步的人 不能向任何人请教
Are you her parent?
你是她的父亲吗？
Well, on paper.
手续上 是的
Huh?
什么？
She was raised in a children's home,
她是在儿童之家长大的
so I'm actually like her legal guardian or guarantor.
所以我实际上是她的法定监护人 或者说是担保人
I see.
明白了
Sixteen and raised in a children's home.
16岁 在儿童之家长大
This story sounds familiar…
感觉我以前听过这个故事
It's just like…
就像…
Doctor, what do you think?
医生 她怎么样？
Isn't there a chance that she's just extremely constipated?
有没有可能她只是严重便秘了？
If she were, she'd be dead.
如果是的话 她早就死了
Everything's fine on that end. No problems today either!
如厕很顺畅 今天也没有问题
Let's do some tests first. Please wait while we get prepared.
首先 我们来做检查 请稍等 我们准备一下
OBSTETRICS AND GYNECOLOGY
（妇产科）
Wait, wait, wait, wait… Huh?! Is she the real deal?!
天啊 什么？她是真的吗？
Is she Ai's look-alike?!
她长得像爱吗？
No, being a longtime fan, I could never mistake her!
不 作为她的老粉丝 我永远不会认错人
Wow! Ai is super cute in person!
爱本人超级可爱
Not now!
现在不行！
My favorite idol is pregnant!
我最喜欢的偶像怀孕了
I'm about to vomit from the shock.
我都快被吓吐了
Ai.
爱
Seriously, how did this happen?
说真的 这是怎么回事？
Like, seriously!
说真的
Why didn't you at least consult me, the CEO?
你为什么不至少 跟我这个总裁商量一下？
Who's the father?
孩子的父亲是谁？
That's…
那是…
a secret!
一个秘密
A secret, eh?! Then I can't do much about that!
一个秘密？那我就无能为力了
Based on the results, you're 20 weeks pregnant with twins.
根据检查结果 你已经怀孕20周了 怀的是双胞胎
-Twins.
双胞胎？
Twins…
双胞胎…
Ai, are you serious about having them?
爱 你真的要生下他们吗？
If the world learns you got pregnant and had kids at 16,
如果全世界都知道 你16岁就怀孕、生子
you and our agency are both over.
你和我们的经纪公司就都完蛋了
Doctor, what do you think?
医生 你怎么看？
You have the right to make the final decision.
决定权在你手中
Think about it very carefully.
做决定前要仔细考虑
As a doctor, that's all I can say.
作为一名医生 我只能说这些
As a doctor, that is.
作为一名医生 就是这样
Whoa, seriously?
真的吗？
IDOL MARRIES COMEDIAN
（偶像嫁给喜剧演员）
And I liked MIU…
我以前喜欢MIU
How timely.
真及时啊
Wait.
等等
If I die now, isn't there a chance I can be reborn as the child of an idol?
如果我现在死了 难道就没有机会 重生成为偶像的孩子吗？
That's a creepy thought.
这是一个可怕的想法
But hey, would you be able to cheer for an idol with a man and a kid?
但是 你能为一个 有男人、有孩子的偶像欢呼吗？
Even if you have a man you like, I'll continue to support you.
即使你有了喜欢的男人 我也会继续支持你
But if you give birth to a child,
但如果你生了孩子
I won't be able to see you rise to the top anymore.
我就再也不能看到你展翅高飞
Fans' opinions are selfish, huh?
粉丝的观点太自私了 是吧？
Don't you think so, Sarina?
你不这么认为吗 纱利奈？
Oh.
哦
Doctor.
医生
Hoshino.
星野
The cold night winds will hurt your body.
寒冷的夜风会伤害你的身体
I'm dressed warm, so don't worry!
我穿得很暖和 所以不用担心
I chose this place because of the CEO's recommendation, but it really is nice!
根据总裁的推荐 我选了这个地方 但这里真的很棒
You can already see the stars really clearly in the evening.
即使在日落时分 你也可以非常清楚地看到星星
You could never see this in Tokyo.
在东京是绝对看不到这个的
Did you come all this way because you'd draw attention in Tokyo?
你大老远跑来这里 是因为你在东京太引人注目吗？
Huh? Have I told you about my job?
什么？我跟你说过我的工作吗？
A long time ago, I had a patient who was a fan of yours.
很久以前 我有个病人是你的粉丝
Yikes.
糟了
Since the doctors are mainly old men here, I thought I wouldn't get noticed.
因为这里的医生大多是老人 我以为我不会引起注意
I guess I can't hide my overflowing aura! What a problem!
我想我无法隐藏我那溢出来的气场 真苦恼呢
Her confidence is cute.
她的自信很可爱
Will you stop being an idol?
你打算不再做偶像了吗？
Why? Nope.
为什么？不是啊
But then…
但是 这样…
I don't have a family, so I've always dreamed of having one.
我没有家人 所以我一直梦想有个家
There are twins in my belly, right?
我肚子里的是双胞胎 对吧？
I'm sure it'll become a lively and fun family then!
我相信那会是一个 充满活力和乐趣的家庭
You're going to have children and continue as an idol.
你会生下孩子 然后继续当偶像
That would mean…
这意味着…
That's right. I'm not going to announce it.
是的 我不会公开的
Idols are just an image. They're creatures that shine with the magic of lies.
偶像只是一种形象 他们是一种闪耀着谎言魔法的生物
Lies are the ultimate form of love.
谎言是爱的终极形式 你知道吗？
Once you can hide a kid or two, that's when you're a first-rate idol!
一旦你能隐藏一两个孩子 那你就是一流的偶像了
No matter how many lies you build up and how tough you have it,
不管你撒了多少谎 不管你有多艰难
it's a fun job where you seemingly sing with joy on stage!
只要你在舞台上幸福地歌唱 这就永远是一份有趣的工作
But I do want that "joy" part to be true though.
但我确实希望“幸福”这部分是真的
Nobody really realizes it, but we have feelings and lives too.
大家都没有意识到 但我们也有感情和生活
The joys of being a mother and the joys of being an idol.
母亲的幸福和偶像的幸福
Normally, it's either or.
通常是不可兼得的
But I want both!
但我都想要
Ai Hoshino is greedy like that.
星野爱很贪婪的
This idol named Ai was much bolder, more cunning, and stronger than I thought.
这个叫爱的偶像 比我想象的要坚强、狡猾、强大得多
She was beaming like the evening star.
她像黄昏的星星一样容光焕发
We've agreed.
我们同意了
Huh?
什么？
The doctor and the fan inside me are in agreement.
我作为医生以及作为粉丝 都同意了
Ai Hoshino.
星野爱
I guarantee that you will safely deliver healthy babies.
我会确保你安全地诞下健康的婴儿
If that's what you call joy, I'll accept it.
如果这就是你所说的幸福 我接受
Since you are hopelessly an idol,
既然你是无可救药的偶像
and I am hopelessly a fan of yours.
那我就是你无可救药的粉丝
Now, going forward,
那从现在开始
let's use an alias at our hospital.
我们暂时在医院里用化名
Okay.
好的
In your case, there's a high chance of a C-section.
根据你的情况 剖腹产的可能性很大
What?
什么？
If the babies have large skulls,
如果婴儿的头骨很大
with your body type, the pelvic opening usually isn't wide enough.
以你的体型 骨盆开口通常不够宽
Really.
真的吗？
A scar on her belly would affect her work.
肚子上有疤会影响她的工作
Doctor, isn't there another way?
医生 难道没有别的办法吗？
Epidural anesthesia, sophrology, no…
硬膜外麻醉、冥想放松法 不…
Anything's fine. My body's super strong anyway.
没关系 反正我的身体超级健康的
Ai…
爱
It'll be fine, I'm sure I can have a natural birth.
别担心 我可以顺产
I mean, they're my kids! I'm sure they'll have small, pretty faces!
我是说 他们是我的孩子 我相信他们会有又小又漂亮的脸
You and your carefree attitude…
你和你不负责任的评论…
Maybe the reason I became a doctor was for this moment.
也许我成为医生的原因 就是为了这一刻
I'll make sure you deliver more safely and successfully.
我会确保你的分娩更安全、更成功
I'll protect your family.
我会保护你的家人
To be honest, I do have mixed feelings about it.
老实说 我对这件事的感情很复杂
But I hide them the best I can.
但我尽量把它们藏起来了
"Lies are a form of love."
“谎言是爱的一种形式”
Stars are incredible because those words are starting to sound real.
明星真不可思议 因为那些话开始听起来很真实
FORTY WEEKS
（40周）
ESTIMATED DUE DATE
（预产期）
Doctor, good night.
医生 您辛苦了
But rush over if I call.
但如果我打电话 你快过来
Okay. My house's close by too.
好 我家也在附近
Well, even if I can't, another doctor will come.
即使我赶不过来 其他医生也会过来
No, I want you, Doctor.
不 我想要你 医生
I'm joking. I'll see you later.
我在开玩笑 待会儿见
Okay.
好的
Once this is over, my connection with Ai will end,
一旦这一切结束 我和爱的联系就会消失
and we'll return to being an idol and a fan.
我们会回归偶像和粉丝的身份
I saw a bit of her real self,
我看到了她真实的一面
but I actually came to like her frank personality.
但实际上 我开始喜欢她直率的性格
I wish for her life to be full of joy from the bottom of my…
我可以从心底祝她幸福…
Are you the doctor in charge of Ai Hoshino?
你是星野爱的医生吗？
She's using an alias.
她用的是化名
Even if you saw her at the hospital,
就算你在医院见过她 你怎么知道她未公开的姓氏？
Do you know her personally? Can I ask your name?
你是她的什么人吗？ 我可以问你的名字吗？
Hey!
喂！
Could he be a stalker? Right when she's about to deliver too…
是跟踪狂吗？ 连她快要生产的时候都不放过
Damn it! Making me run through these mountain paths…
该死 让我在这山路上狂奔
Where'd he go?
他去哪儿了？
Ugh, that scared me. My mind went blank all of a sudden.
吓死我了 我的脑子一下子一片空白
Oh, my phone.
我的手机
Did Ai go into labor?
爱要生了吗？
Where's my phone?
我的手机在哪里？
It's so dark, I can't tell.
太黑了 我看不清
Wait, my body won't move.
等等 我的身体不能动了
I need to hurry and go.
我得赶紧走
I promised her that I'll make sure she delivers healthy babies.
我向她保证过 会让她生下健康的宝宝
I need to get up,
我得起来
and help deliver her children.
帮她接生…
Haven't you ever thought, "What if I was born as the child of a celebrity?"
你有没有想过 “如果我是名人的孩子呢？”
What if you had the looks and connections since the time you were born?
你一出生就有那样的长相和人脉？
If I die now, isn't there a chance I can be reborn as the child of an idol?
如果我现在死了 难道就没有机会 重生成为偶像的孩子吗？
If I could be reborn…
如果我重生…
I never seriously thought about it.
我从没认真想过
I mean, isn't that right?
我是说 难道不是这样吗？
I never thought something like that would occur to me.
我从没想过这样的事会发生在我身上
I always thought someone like me would go to hell once they died.
我一直以为 像我这样的人死后会下地狱
But…
但是…
Hm?
什么？
Once I woke up, I was in heaven.
一醒来 我就到了天堂
This is me now.
这就是现在的我
What a good boy, Aquamarine!
真是个好孩子 爱久爱海
Anyhow, I've been given a ridiculous name.
总之 她给我取了一个荒谬的名字
Currently, I am living as the idol Ai Hoshino's son.
目前 我是偶像星野爱的儿子
Please don't ask me why.
请不要问我为什么
Even for me, it took a long time to accept this reality.
即使对我来说 接受这个现实也花了很长时间
Have I been reborn?
我重生了吗？
Or is it called "reincarnation" nowadays?
或者现在管这叫“转世”？
Why do I have memories of my past life? How does this system work?
为什么我有前世的记忆？ 这个系统是怎么工作的？
I am a doctor after all. I intend to uncover this system one day.
我毕竟是个医生 我打算有一天揭开这个系统的秘密
However…
然而
For now, I want to indulge in this baby life.
现在 我想要享受这种婴儿生活
This environment where my favorite idol completely pampers me
这个我最喜欢的偶像 完全宠爱我的环境
really heals my exhausted mind from my adult life.
真的治愈了我作为社会人疲惫的心灵
G-Goo-goo…
咕咕 嘎嘎
Coming.
来了
Oh yeah, there's another resident in this house.
对 这房子里还有一个住户
What is it, Ruby?
怎么了 露比？
Ruby Hoshino, the baby born as my twin.
星野露比 我的双胞胎妹妹
This one has a less damaging name.
这个名字的破坏性较小
If it isn't too late, I'd like to switch.
如果还来得及的话 我想换一下
What's wrong, Aqua?
怎么了 阿夸？
That one's Ruby. You call yourself their mother?
那个是露比啦 你这个当妈妈的还不认得孩子？
I can't help it, it's hard for me to remember people's faces and names.
没办法 我很难记住人们的面孔和名字
Isn't that awful? Men in Japan tend to idealize the mother figure too much.
那不是很可怕吗？ 日本男性倾向于过于理想化母亲形象
You don't even have a passport. Don't say something so global!
你连护照都没有 不要说这么全球化的话
Besides, you don't even accept overseas shoots!
再说了 你又不去海外拍戏
But I can remember the people that I think have talent, CEO Sato.
但我能记住我觉得有才华的人 佐藤总裁
Close. My name is Saitou, you shitty idol.
闭嘴 我叫斋藤 你这个不称职的偶像
ICHIGO PRODUCTION CEO ICHIGO SAITOU
（莓制作公司 总裁 斋藤一护）
More importantly! Ai the idol will make her return today.
不管怎样 偶像爱从今天开始回归
We're discussing the plan from here.
我们在这里讨论计划
Your first comeback will be tonight's music show.
你的首次复出将是今晚的音乐秀
It's live, but you good to go?
是直播 你准备好了吗？
Of course.
当然
While Ai is at work, my wife will watch the kids.
爱工作时 我妻子会照看孩子
ICHIGO PRODUCTION MIYAKO SAITOU
（莓制作公司 斋藤京子）
Your wife's so young.
你老婆太年轻了
The other members are also creeped out by you favoring young girls.
其他成员也被你偏爱年轻女孩吓到了
Never knew. I'll be careful.
从来不知道 我会小心的
Can't I bring these two with me?
我不能带他们两个去现场吗？
Of course not!
当然不能
Don't forget!
别忘了
If the world finds out you're a 16-year-old mom with two kids,
如果全世界发现 你是个16岁的母亲 有两个孩子
your career as an idol will end there.
你的偶像生涯就到此为止了
I'll be asked to take responsibility and my agency will be done for.
我要承担责任 我的公司也会完蛋
Everyone goes to hell together!
大家一起下地狱！
The paperwork to city hall, shopping, no bringing the kids anywhere!
去市政厅办事、购物 总之去任何地方 都不能带孩子
Only if there's an absolute emergency,
只有在绝对紧急的情况下
you go out by saying that you're babysitting our kids!
你可以说你在照顾我们的孩子
What?
什么？
What a pain, right Ruby?
好烦人 对吧 露比？
That's Aqua.
那是阿夸
Ai will probably go under the really bad type of moms.
爱可能会成为非常糟糕的妈妈
But the CEO and his wife will generously support us,
但是总裁和他的妻子 会慷慨地支持我们
so maybe it'll work out somehow.
所以也许会有办法解决
Rehearsal's soon. Let's move.
彩排马上开始 我们走
Okay!
好
Oops.
哎哟
That was close! I almost flashed my boobs to you.
好险啊 我差点在你们面前露胸了
Just keep them covered outside.
在外面要遮好了
No, this isn't good. I'm too worried about this girl!
不 不好 我太担心这个女孩了
B Komachi is on set!
B小町上场
We're B Komachi, nice to meet you.
我们是B小町 很高兴见到你
Yes, nice to meet you.
是的 很高兴见到你们
I don't even have babysitting experience.
我根本没有当过保姆
Why do I have to do this?
我为什么要这么做？
Ai has finally returned today!
爱终于回来了
Are you okay? Are you eating well?
还好吗？有好好吃饭吗？
Yes! I'm eating lots!
是的 我吃了很多
Good, she's doing okay.
很好 她没事
Oh yeah, speaking of eating, my boy was--
对了 说到吃饭 我的孩子…
My boy?
“我的孩子”？
I meant my kitten! I adopted him recently while I was taking a break.
我是说我的小猫 我在休息的时候收养了它
Ah.
是吗？
-Actually, I don't know about her. -I'm always saying weird things.
-果然是不太行啊 -我总是说奇怪的话
You'll be on camera in 30 seconds.
30秒后你们就会出镜
Give us a good performance!
期待你们带来精彩表演 有劳了
-Yes! -Yes, we will!
-好的 -好的 谢谢
You know B Komachi?
你知道B小町吗？
Nah. Not interested.
不知道 不感兴趣
I heard their music, but they're average. Neither good nor bad.
我听过她们的音乐 不好也不坏 就很普通
But I guess this is what sells.
但我想这就是卖点
Right.
对
Mass-produced idols.
量产偶像
We have to find a compliment, but what's there to say?
我们必须找到赞美的话 但有什么可说的呢？
Isn't the center's face the only praiseworthy thing?
C位的容貌难道不是 唯一值得称赞的东西吗？
I know the group but haven't heard of them in months.
我知道这个组合 但好几个月没听到他们的消息了
-Who squeezed them in? -Underground idols…
-谁让他们插进来的？ -地下的偶像…
Ichigo Production. Don't know them.
莓制作公司 不认识他们
One's got boobs. Make her do gravure.
其中一个有胸 让她来拍平面照
Call her to dinner for the producer.
叫她来参加制片人的晚宴
In this industry, there are lies and calculations under the smiles.
在这个行业里 微笑之下隐藏着谎言和算计
10 SECONDS
（倒计时十秒）
An empty slot isn't allowed in broadcasting.
直播中不允许出现空时槽
And to maximize the performance of any performer, even the staff will lie.
为了鼓励表演者呈现最佳表现 工作人员也会撒谎
Same with the higher-ups.
高层也是一样
They pretend to make good work, but they're fixated on numbers.
他们假装是为了制作出好节目 但其实只关注数字
Jeez, bring it on.
-老天 要上了 -六、五、四…
Our Ai…
我们的爱
is a hardcore liar!
是个彻头彻尾的骗子！
That CEO's pretty crazy.
那位总裁太疯狂了
If Ai's secret is exposed, he risks losing everything.
如果爱的秘密被曝光 他就有可能失去一切
But I can understand. There's no way you can't be crazy for her.
但我能理解 你不可能不为她疯狂
If the light before you is too bright, people simply get burned.
当面前的光太过强烈时 人们会被灼伤
You get pulled in like moths drawn to a flame.
你就会像飞蛾扑火一样 被卷入其中
Even if your wings burn off, you can't stop.
即使你的翅膀烧了 你也停不下来
I'm no exception. I'm glad that I can watch over Ai this close.
我也不例外 我很高兴 我能这么近距离地观察爱
I'm almost thankful to the guy who killed me.
我几乎要感谢那个杀了我的家伙了
If this rebirth is a miracle caused by my perseverance toward her,
如果这次重生 是我对她的坚持带来的奇迹
it makes sense.
那就说得通了
To be honest, I wanted to help her deliver normal children, but…
其实 我本意是想 帮她接生出健康的孩子 但是
It's beyond my powers. You can't win against the supernatural.
这超出了我的能力 你赢不了超自然力量
So I'm just going to enjoy myself.
那么 我要好好享受了
Wait.
等等
N Station's on already! Why didn't you wake me up?!
N站已经开始了？ 你为什么不叫醒我？
Oh my gosh! Mama's too cute!
我的天啊 妈妈太可爱了！
All viewers should pay hundreds of millions to watch!
所有观众都应该花上亿来观看
Isn't her expression when she turns just awesome?
她转身时的表情很厉害吧？
She's so wicked, she might as well be a demon! My gosh!
她太神奇了 她是绝美恶魔吗？ 我的天啊
I just changed my diaper, but I might wet myself again!
我刚换了尿布 但我可能又尿了
She has a great face, great style, and great singing.
漂亮的脸蛋、 活泼的风格、优美的歌声
Our mom is seriously too talented!
我们的妈妈真是太有才华了
I gotta rewatch the recording right away!
我得马上再看一遍录播
Live shows are meant to be watched live, so why didn't you wake me?
现场表演就是要现场看的 你为什么不叫醒我？
These bodies get ridiculously sleepy, so let's both cooperate!
这些身体都很容易困 所以我们合作吧
I tried waking you several times.
我叫了你好几次
Oh, seriously?
真的吗？
This idiot was also reborn from someone, just like me.
这个白痴也是从别人身上重生的 就像我一样
I actually noticed it pretty early on.
实际上 我很早就注意到了
Huh? Drop dead!
什么？去死吧！
You apes who can't understand talent and beauty!
你们这些不懂妈妈的美和才华的猩猩
Her performance quality proves she's better!
她的表演质量证明她更优秀
It's inevitable that management would favor her!
管理层肯定会偏袒她
I bet you're an ugly hag anyway!
反正我打赌你是个丑八怪
Look at a mirror before you say that again, you bag!
说话前先照照镜子 你个混蛋！
Ugh, can't believe this!
简直不敢相信
She was looking up, "B Komachi Ai,"
她在搜“B小町爱”关键词
and having fierce reply battles with haters on social media.
并在社交媒体上和讨厌她的人 展开激烈的论战
Are you…
你和我
the same as me?
一样吗？
Uh…
呃…
A baby just talked! How creepy!
一个婴儿刚刚说话了！好吓人啊！
You too.
你也是啊
I can't help but think
我不禁想
how I really wanted to help Ai deliver some normal children.
我真的很想帮爱接生几个正常的孩子
Oh my gosh!
果然！
Recording it once to watch it forever is wicked cost-efficient!
只录一次就能永远看下去 这太划算了
Not some weird twins like us.
而不是像我们这样奇怪的双胞胎
Ai.
爱
You liar. How dare you have kids!
你这个骗子 你竟敢有孩子！
Why?
为什么？
You tricked me!
你骗了我！
Aqua.
阿夸
Are you hungry? You want my milk?
你饿了吗？你想喝母乳吗？
Oh, you don't?
你没有？
Aqua sure likes his bottle.
阿夸很喜欢他的奶瓶
Look at him drink!
看他喝的
As an adult, I feel that having an idol breastfeed me crosses the line.
作为一个成年人 我觉得让偶像给我喂奶太过分了
Yes, yes.
是的
My milk again?
又想喝母乳？
Ruby sure likes breast milk.
露比喜欢母乳呢
This bastard…
这个混蛋
It's time for work.
该去工作了
Okay!
好的
I'll be going then.
那我走了
Have a nice day.
一切顺利
Bye-bye!
出门啦
Can't you show some restraint?
你就不能收敛一点吗？
Why?
为什么？
As her daughter, the law of nature says I must suckle on Mama's boobs.
作为她的女儿 自然法则说我必须吸妈妈的母乳
It's a natural right that I've been granted.
这是我被赋予的自然权利
Just asking, but were you a female in your past life too?
随便问问 你前世也是女性吗？
Yeah.
是的
Then, I guess that's borderline okay.
那么 我想这是可以接受的
Your jealousy is gross!
你的嫉妒心真恶心
Well, a grown man breastfeeding does sound ethically wrong!
成年男性喝母乳 听起来很不道德
I'm so glad I was born a female, so I can rightfully suckle on boobs!
我很高兴我前世是女性 所以我可以理所当然地吃母乳
From my ethical perspective, that's still wrong though.
从我的道德角度来看 这仍然是错误的
Poor Mama.
可怜的妈妈
She would never think her own child is her otaku. That's seriously gross.
她绝不会认为自己的孩子 是她的宅男粉丝 真是有点恶心呢
Oh, poor Mama. I'll protect you for life.
可怜的妈妈 我会保护你一辈子
You're definitely more gross.
你才更恶心吧
I need to change my diaper, so go away.
我想换尿布 所以走开
Sure, sure.
好的
Why do I have to do this job?
为什么我要做这份工作？
Aren't I the CEO's wife?
我不是总裁的妻子吗？
I married him because I thought I could work with pretty boys.
我嫁给他是因为 以为可以跟美少年一起工作
But instead, my job is to care for a 16-year-old idol's kids?!
但相反 我的工作是 照顾一个16岁偶像的孩子？
A single mom with an unknown father?!
她是个单亲妈妈 父亲不详？
That's way too shady!
这太可疑了！
First of all, I didn't get married to become a babysitter!
首先 我结婚不是为了当保姆！
Huh?
什么？
Being able to serve Mama should bring you nothing but pure joy.
能为妈妈服务是一种纯粹的幸福
What's wrong with her head?
她脑子怎么回事？
Well, there is some validity to what she's saying.
她说的话有一定的道理
Ugh.
对
Wait, isn't this a cover-up of a scandal?
等等 这不是在掩盖丑闻吗？
I know.
我知道了
If I sell this story to a tabloid, I could become rich.
如果我把这个故事卖给小报 我就能发财了
Just screw everything! Let's do this!
去他的！我们开始吧！
Uh, this is bad! What do we do, kill her?!
太糟糕了 我们该怎么办？杀了她吗？
Not possible, we're no match for an adult.
不可能 我们不是成年人的对手
I was just kidding about that, but were you being serious?
我只是在开玩笑 但你是认真的吗？
If we let her be, she'll surely become a threat.
如果我们放过她 她肯定会成为一个威胁
But…
但是…
What do we do?!
我们该怎么办？
She's taking pictures of the maternity handbook!
她在拍孕妇手册
Rather, this is our chance.
相反 这是我们的机会
I got an idea.
我有个主意
With this money, I'll push my host up to the top of the monthly rankings.
有了这笔钱 我就能把我喜欢的牛郎 推到每月排名的首位
Oh, pitiful girl.
可怜的女孩
The thirst in your heart cannot be quenched by champagne.
你心中的渴望 香槟是无法满足的
Who's there?!
谁在那儿？
I-I am the messenger of god.
我…我是上帝的使者
Your reckless actions can no longer be overlooked!
你鲁莽的行为不能再被忽视了
Messenger of god?
上帝的使者？
Wait, a baby just talk… No way.
等等 一个婴儿刚刚说话了 不可能
According to your common sense, can babies speak? Face the truth.
你的常识告诉你婴儿会说话吗？ 面对现实吧
Uh-uh! Even if you say god sent you, I don't believe in that stuff, so…
就算你说是上帝派你来的 我也不信那种鬼话 所以…
Oh, I know! I'm getting punked!
我知道 我被耍了
It must be a show that Ai will be on to punk the manager! That's it!
一定是爱要愚弄经纪人的节目 就是这样
This sure is an elaborate prank. Where are the cameras?
他们在这上面下了不少功夫 摄影机在哪里？
Guess it was too far-fetched.
我想这太牵强了
Come on, Ruby, climbing onto the table is danger…
过来 露比 爬到桌子上很危险
Know your place. I am the incarnation of Amaterasu.
摆正自己的位置 我是太阳女神的化身
The god you people speak of.
你们口中的神
God?
神？
You have been blinded by money, nearly abandoning your destined mission.
你被金钱蒙蔽了双眼 差点放弃你的“天命”
Destined mission?
天命？
Ai Hoshino was chosen by the god of entertainment.
星野爱被娱乐之神选中了
And her children are twins who are also destined for a great mission.
而她的双胞胎孩子 他们也注定要肩负伟大的使命
'Tis your destined mission to protect them.
你的使命就是保护他们
Your actions go against the gods.
你的行为违背了诸神
If this lasts, divine punishment awaits you.
如果这种情况持续下去 就会有“天罚”在等着你
Divine punishment?!
天罚？
What divine punishment?!
什么天罚？
Specifically?!
具体是什么？
Specifically? Specifically…
具体是什么？具体是…
You die.
你会死
Yes, you die!
对 你会死！
No! That's too specific!
不要 这太具体了
What should I do?
我该怎么办？
The answer is simple.
答案很简单
You must protect our secret.
保护妈妈和我们的秘密
And care for us by following everything we say.
关心我们 按我们说的做
Everything…
按你们…
If you do, getting remarried to a handsome actor may no longer be just a dream.
如果你这样做了 那跟英俊的演员再婚可能不再是梦想
For real?!
真的吗？
I'll do it! I'll do anything you say!
我会做的 你说什么我就做什么
Even lick your insoles!
连舔你的鞋垫都行
That will not be necessary.
没有那个必要
Remarrying a hot guy!
再嫁一个帅哥
Was this okay?
这样做对吗？
Either way, there's a limit to what infants can do.
不管怎样 婴儿的能力是有限的
Now, we can go outside too.
现在 我们也可以出去了
Yay!
太好了
But that was pretty good acting back there.
但你刚才演得很好
Were you an actress somewhere?
你当过演员吗？
Uh-uh. My first time.
我第一次
First time? Didn't you do plays at school?
第一次？你上学时不演戏吗？
I was raised in an unusual environment.
我是在一个不寻常的环境中长大的
Hm. Then it must be talent.
那一定是天赋了
Maybe you're a future actress.
也许你将来会成为演员
The future…
将来…
I've never even thought of it.
我从来没想过
I have a sister now.
我现在有一个妹妹了
She's a weird girl who's an idol otaku.
她是个奇怪的女孩 是偶像宅
However…
然而…
Ai's dancing is so sharp! She seriously has charisma!
爱的舞跳得真棒 她真的很有魅力
Hm.
是吗？
I like Ai the most in the world,
在这个世界上 我最喜欢爱
but I like you just as much, Doctor!
但我也同样喜欢你 医生
Her passion whenever she spoke about Ai
她对爱的热情
was exactly like yours,
和你一模一样
Sarina.
纱利奈
What? Did you call me?
什么？你叫我了吗？
My bad, did I wake you?
我的错 我吵醒你了吗？
No, I didn't.
我没叫你
If you're gonna sleep, go to the futon.
如果你要睡觉 就回被褥上去
Well, yeah.
也是啦
It can't be…
这怎么可能
Sarina was my name in my past life anyway.
不管怎么说 纱利奈是我前世的名字
A few months had passed since Ai made her return as an idol.
爱以偶像身份回归已经好几个月了
B Komachi's great comeback…
B小町的隆重回归
was not exactly happening.
效果并不如预期
My salary this month is 200 thousand yen.
我这个月的工资是二十万日元
Hey, isn't our agency's salary too low?
我们公司的工资是不是太低了？
Didn't our last song rank third on the Oricon Singles Chart?
我们不是在 日本公信榜单曲榜上排名第三吗？
Isn't the middleman's cut too big?
中间商的分成是不是太多了？
What's the matter suddenly?
怎么突然说这个？
We don't do manufacturing to distribution. We're just a tiny talent agency.
我们不生产、不分销 只是个很小的经纪公司而已
You should know we have low profits.
你应该知道我们的利润很低
I realized the world is all about money.
我意识到这个世界到处都要用钱
What an ugly truth you realized.
你意识到了一个丑陋的事实
It's fun being an idol,
当偶像很有趣
so I wouldn't have minded staying this way if it were just myself.
所以如果只有我自己 我不介意一直当下去
But to send these kids to a good school or let them do extracurricular activities…
但是把这俩孩子送去好学校 或者让他们参加课外活动…
To give them more options, I need to become even more popular,
为了给他们更多的选择 我需要变得更受欢迎
and earn more money, right?
不赚很多钱 就实现不了 对吗？
At this rate, I can't make these kids happy.
照这样下去 我没法让这俩孩子幸福
I wish a job for a commercial or movie would come in.
希望能接到一个广告或电影的工作
A big company at that.
最好是一家大公司
First off, quit buying that expensive ice cream.
首先 别再买昂贵的冰淇淋了
I'm off to my lessons.
我要去上课了
Be good kids while I'm gone.
我不在的时候要乖一点
Hey, don't idols make like a million yen a month?
偶像不是一个月赚一百万日元吗？
Of course not.
当然不是
Of course not?!
当然不是？
Royalties for music and TV appearance fees are split between the members.
音乐版税和电视出场费由成员们平分
If their merch doesn't sell, concerts are in the red.
如果周边卖不出去 音乐会就会出现赤字
And costume fees are deducted from the salary.
服装从工资中扣除
Only a handful of idols make a million yen a month.
只有少数偶像能赚到一百万
What, the money isn't reaching the hardest working people? This world's doomed!
什么？钱没到最辛苦的人手里吗？ 这个世界完蛋了
Oh, I know!
我知道了
Why don't all otakus take turns offering their livers to Ai, and we sell them…
为什么不让宅男们轮流把自己的肝 献给爱 然后我们卖掉它们
Your mindset is what's doomed.
你的心态是注定要失败的
Stop with your post-apocalyptic religious views.
你这后启示录般的黑暗宗教观点 差不多停停了
She can sing, dance, and has a great face.
她会唱歌、跳舞 有一张漂亮的脸
She takes lessons, does voice training, and practices choreography at home.
她在家里上课 接受声乐训练、练习舞蹈
B Komachi should be a popular group…
B小町应该是一个很受欢迎的组合
Hey, manager!
经纪人
Why isn't our Ai getting any work?!
为什么我们的爱没有得到任何工作？
You shitty management! Market her more!
你们这些该死的管理层 多推销她啊
It's not as easy as you say.
这可不像你们说的那么容易
To sum it up, idol groups are a system where about a dozen people work as one
总而言之 偶像团体是这样一个系统
to fight over the same jobs against a single celebrity.
一群偶像和一位明星争夺同样的工作
We're barely getting work selling as a set right now.
我们现在作为团体销售 都很难接到工作
If she wants to work alone, that'll be a tough wall to break through.
如果她想单飞 会经历重重困难
There are girls who graduate being idols to work solo,
有些女孩从偶像团体毕业后单飞
but can't get jobs alone, so they work at high-end restaurants in Roppongi.
但找不到单人的工作 只得在六本木的高级餐厅打工
And there are tons of former idols who become "Minato Girls"
还有很多前偶像变成了“港区女子”
who are paid to drink to get by.
靠陪酒来过日子
I don't really know, but…
我真的不知道 但是…
Tokyo's a scary place.
东京是个可怕的地方
I do recognize that Ai is amazing.
我同意爱很棒
But that's only within the idol field.
但只是在偶像领域
You need a special skill of your own to survive in the world of entertainment.
你需要一种特殊的技能 才能在娱乐圈中生存
Because jobs that you can profit from won't be for "somebody in B Komachi,"
能够挣大钱的工作是不会因为你是 区区“B小町的某个成员”找上门来
they have to be jobs that only Ai can do.
必须是只有爱才能做的工作才可以
Just being an overachiever as an idol isn't enough.
仅仅成为一个优等生 作为偶像是不够的
Ai, you look a little down.
爱 你看起来有点沮丧
You just recovered, so don't push yourself, okay?
你刚刚康复 所以不要勉强自己 好吗？
That's not it!
不是这样的
I missed lunch, so I'm super hungry!
我错过了午饭 现在超级饿的
What's that? Your foodie image?
那是什么？你的吃货人设？
-Let's do that part again. -Sure, okay!
-让我们再跳一次刚才那部分 -当然 好的
I can't get into the mood.
有点进入不了状态啊
I'm gonna egosurf.
上网看看吧
GOOD OR BAD, AI HAS A PRO'S SMILE IT LOOKS INHUMAN…
（有好有坏 爱的笑容太专业了 看起来不像人类）
He's got me there.
被他发现了
CONGRATULATIONS B KOMACHI
（祝B小町公演成功）
A promotional event!
推介音乐会！
A mini concert!
小型现场演出！
This is something you can only win in a lottery!
堪比中头奖
This is my first time properly seeing Mama's stage.
这是我第一次亲眼看到妈妈的舞台
Listen carefully.
听好了
I brought you two because you insisted,
我带你们来是因为你们坚持
but I'm the one who's going to get reprimanded if the CEO finds out.
但如果总裁发现了 被骂的人是我
No cheering, running, or talking!
不许欢呼、不许奔跑、不许说话
Keep your pacifiers on and stay quiet, okay?
戴上安抚奶嘴 保持安静 好吗？
That's right, Ruby. Just don't do anything that catches people's attention.
没错 露比 不要做任何引起别人注意的事情
Anything that tips off our relation to Ai--
任何能说明我们跟爱关系的事…
You don't have to tell me.
你不必告诉我
You saw how upset Mama was.
你看到了吧？妈妈的情绪不好
I'm here because I'm worried about her.
我来这里是因为我担心她
We're not here to have fun…
我们不是来找乐子的
Today, we have three members of B Komachi here!
今天 我们请来了B小町的三位成员
B Komachi!
B小町！
GOOD OR BAD, AI HAS A PRO'S SMILE
（有好有坏 爱的笑容太专业了）
Whatever you say, I am a pro after all.
不管你说什么 我毕竟是专业的
IT LOOKS INHUMAN…
（看起来不像人类）
I don't really understand.
我真的不明白
Aren't you the ones demanding me to be inhuman?
难道不是你们 要求我变得不像人类的吗？
I study my smile in the mirror and modify it to the millimeter.
我对着镜子研究我的微笑 进行毫米级的调整
How I narrow my eyes, how I grin…
我如何眯起眼睛、如何微笑
It's all calculated.
这一切都是经过计算的
I always put on the smile that pleases people the most.
我总是露出最讨人喜欢的笑容
I am made of lies after all.
我终究是由谎言组成的
…Goo-goo! Ga-ga! Goo-goo…
咕咕！嘎嘎！
What's with those babies?! They're doing the otagei!
那俩孩子是怎么回事？ 他们在跳打艺舞
Their movements are too sharp for infants!
他们的动作对婴儿来说太超过了
What did you say about being worried? You're enjoying it more than anyone!
你们不是说担心她吗？ 怎么比任何人都享受
It was pure instinct!
这纯粹是本能
Wow.
天啊
What the… That's amazing.
什么…这太神奇了
My babies are so cuuute!
我的宝贝们太可爱了！
Retweeted 210,000 times.
转发21万次
Even the reposted video has two million views.
即使是转发的视频 也有二百万的点击量
I know that baby content trends easily, but this is a little too…
我知道婴儿内容很容易流行 但这有点太…
Come with me.
跟我来一下
WHAT'S HER NAME?
（她叫什么名字？）
DID AI SMILE LIKE THIS? MY IMPRESSION OF HER CHANGED
（爱笑成这样吗？ 我对她的印象变了）
LIKE TROUBLESOME OTAKUS
（像惹麻烦的御宅族）
THIS IS IT! THIS!
（就是这样 这样！）
I see.
明白了
So this is what you want.
所以这是你想要的啊
Now, I know!
现在我知道了
One year later.
一年后
We became old enough to walk and talk without drawing suspicion.
我们长大了 可以走路、说话了 不会引起怀疑
And my sister…
还有我妹妹…
Mama! Mama!
妈妈
Hmm?
什么？
Pat me on the head!
拍拍我的头
There, there.
好的
She became the definition of a creepy spoiled fan who calls their idol "Mama."
她成了一个被宠坏的粉丝 叫自己的偶像“妈妈”
Ahh, I'm ascending to heaven!
我要升上极乐世界了
Where did you learn such difficult words?
你从哪儿学来这么难的词？
Don't tell me…
别告诉我…
Umm.
那个…
Can Ai be suspecting us?
难道…爱会怀疑我们吗？
You're like an insane prodigy.
你就像个疯狂的天才
That being a needless worry, we're spending our days in peace.
这是一个不必要的担心 我们在平静地度过我们的日子
Must be genetic.
肯定是遗传的
Modeling, radio assistant,
模特、电台助理
Ai was steadily gaining work.
爱的工作稳步增加
And her job today could be called the culmination of her efforts.
你可以说今天是她努力的结果
I'm excited about your first TV drama, Mama!
我很期待你的第一部电视剧 妈妈
It's a minor role though.
不过这只是一个次要角色
Listen up, you two.
听好了 你们两个
I'm taking you both because you insisted,
我带你们俩去是因为你们坚持要去
but don't ever call Ai "Mama" on the set.
但千万不要在片场叫爱“妈妈”
Don't forget that you're supposed to be my kids.
别忘了 你们应该是我的孩子
Yes, yes. Mama, pat me on the head.
是的 妈妈 拍拍我的头
Me too, Mama!
我也是 妈妈
Mama, gimme me an allowance.
妈妈 给我零用钱吧
I'm Ai from Ichigo Production. Nice working with you today.
我是莓制作公司的爱 今天的工作 请多多关照
Nice working with you.
请多关照
Is something wrong, Director?
有什么问题吗 导演？
No, not really.
没 算不上
He's kind of scary.
他有点吓人
His face is.
他的脸吓人
Huh? Who are these kids?
什么？这些孩子是谁？
Uh, these are my kids.
这些是我的孩子
A manager bringing their kids on set?
经纪人带孩子来片场？
The work-style reform bill?
《工作方式改革法案》？
Huh?
什么？
Times have changed.
时代变了 毕竟也有人带狗来片场
-Are you sleep-deprived? -Can you tell?
-你睡眠不足吗？ -你能看出来吗？
Twins! How cute!
双胞胎 真可爱
Oh, I think this girl is that gravure model.
我觉得这个女孩就是那个平面模特
That one's "the young actress that's too cute for her talent."
那个“可爱的天赋型年轻女演员”
Goo-goo! Ga-ga!
咕咕 嘎嘎
Stop trying to act cute.
别装可爱了
This is bad. My body can't take this.
很糟糕 我的身体承受不了
Huh?
什么？
You're that manager's kid.
你是那个经纪人的孩子
I don't mind you being here, but I'll kick you out if you start crying.
我不介意你在这里 但如果你开始哭 我就把你赶出去
Uh, we're babies, but we shall make sure to never cause such interruptions!
我们虽然是小孩 但永远不会打扰到你们
We understand it is the minimum rule to not disturb the filming process.
我们明白 不干扰拍摄是最低要求
We kindly ask for your continued business with Ai…
我们恳请您继续与爱…
This baby talks like crazy!
这孩子说话像疯了一样
Where did you learn those words?
你从哪里学来的这些词？
A bit on YouTube.
在YouTube上学了些
YouTube's incredible! Times have changed!
YouTube太不可思议了 时代变了
I've seen many mature child actors, but I've never seen one this mature.
我见过很多成熟的童星
Are you an actor too?
你也是演员吗？
Well, I don't do that type of thing.
不 演戏那种事 我不做的…
You'd be interesting to have on screen. I wanna use you for something.
你在荧幕上会很有趣 我会用得上你
This is my card.
这是我的名片
If you join an agency, call me.
如果你加入了经纪公司 就给我打电话
No, if you want to give me work, please pass it to Ai instead.
不了 如果你要给我工作 就转给爱吧
Oh, that idol.
那个偶像啊
She has an excellent face. If she's lucky, she'll survive.
她有一张漂亮的脸 幸运的话 她能活下来
Luck? When she has an excellent face?
已经长得很漂亮了 还需要好运吗？
Listen, there are three types of actors.
听着 演员分三种
Look at them there.
看看他们
One is the star actor.
一种是明星演员
Their job is to bring in customers.
他们的工作是吸引客户
They serve the same purpose as an ad, so the pay is good.
他们是公司的门面 所以薪水很高
Next is the talented type.
其次是才华横溢的类型
They ensure the quality of the work. Their job is to uphold the company brand.
他们保证了作品的质量 他们的工作是维护公司品牌
The last one is the new face.
最后一种是新面孔
No one's expecting acting skills from them.
没人指望他们有演技
As long as they're refreshing to see on screen, they pass.
只要他们在荧幕上令人耳目一新 就会通过
It's also to let future stars build experience.
这也是为了让未来的明星积累经验
Well, it's an industry-wide investment.
也算是全行业的投资了
This means all those new faces there are in the stage of being an investment.
也就是说 所有这些新面孔都处于投资阶段
You either win the viewers or the staff.
你要么赢得观众 要么赢得工作人员
Without either, you'll be replaced by the next newbie.
哪个都没赢 你就会被下一个新人取代
If any of those new faces survive within this set, it's a big success.
如果这些新面孔中有人能在片场 存活下来 那就是一个巨大的成功
That's the world we're in.
这就是我们所在的世界
The ones who survive are only the top class.
幸存下来的都是一流人才
Hm. Then she'll be fine.
那她就没事了
Because Ai is a top-class idol.
因为爱是顶级偶像
Uh, there's no point in being a top-class idol.
成为顶级偶像 没有任何意义
Huh?
什么？
Director! The run-through is ready.
导演 排练已经准备好了
Okay, I'll watch it here.
好的 我在这里看
Ready…
预备
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
You want me to ask Toma?
你要我问托马吗？
Hey, don't ever do that, okay?!
千万别问他 好吗？
Aren't you always with him?
你不是一直和他在一起吗？
Her acting is average, but she draws attention.
她的演技一般 但很引人注目
Right? She was saying earlier…
对吧？她之前说过…
On stage, you have to look cute for everyone from every angle,
在舞台上 你呈现给每个人的 每个角度都必须是可爱的
but you just need to be cute for one person here, the camera.
但在这里 你只需要 在一个人面前显得可爱 那就是镜头
If it's the same as a music video, it's my specialty.
如果制作过程和音乐视频一样 那就是我的专长
You did it! I'll…
你做到了 我…
A music video perspective?
音乐视频的视角？
Times have changed.
时代变了
Oh! It's really good, so you should definitely watch it!
真的很好看 你一定要看
I'll even lend you the DVD!
我可以把光盘借给你看
You're too loud.
太大声了
It's too early. You can always challenge…
太早了 你可以随时挑战…
I can't wait for Mama's acting!
我等不及看妈妈的演技了
We did take a lot of scenes.
我们确实拍了很多
It's almost time.
时间差不多了
It started!
开始了
Are you kind of upset?
你有点不高兴吗？
No.
没有
Did I do something?
我做了什么吗？
This is the scene!
是这场
What's with him?
他怎么了？
Oh, it's Mama!
是妈妈
Close up on her!
镜头快拉进点啊
Huh? Is something wrong?
什么？有什么不对吗？
Wait, Toma!
等等 托马
Miki, why are you here?
三木 你怎么来了？
That's why we should've never met.
所以我们才不应该见面
What do you mean by that?
你这是什么意思？
What? That's it?!
什么？就这样？
That was only one scene!
只有一幕而已
They cut out too much!
他们剪得太多了
Was my acting that bad?
我的表演有那么糟糕吗？
That's not true!
那不是真的
Yes?
什么事？
Hey, Director! What happened?!
喂 导演 怎么回事？
Oh, the mature baby.
是那个小大人啊
You didn't use Ai at all!
你根本就没用爱的镜头
Oh, that. It was a shame when it turned out so well.
那个啊 本来效果很好的 真可惜
Then how come?!
那是怎么回事？
The lead actress's agency
女主演的经纪公司
markets her as "the young actress that's too cute for her talent."
将她定位为 “可爱的天赋型年轻女演员”
So, what would happen if a cuter face is in the same shot?
那么 如果一张更可爱的脸 出现在同一个镜头里会发生什么呢？
That'd affect her marketing image, right?
这会影响她的营销形象 对吧？
Ai was just too cute for that screen.
爱在荧幕上太可爱了
So due to the higher-ups' wishes,
因此 根据上头的意思
we had to edit her out as much as possible.
我们不得不尽可能地把她剪掉
What's with that…
什么鬼？
The cast's screen time is set by the power balance between companies.
演员的出场时间 是由公司之间的权力平衡决定的
So think of it as an accident.
所以把它想象成一个意外吧
I can't accept it.
我不能接受
You can dream of working in showbiz, but showbiz is no glamorous dream.
你可以梦想在娱乐圈工作 但娱乐圈并不是一个迷人的美梦
It's not a place for art, but for business.
这里不是搞艺术的地方 是做生意的地方
But I do understand your point, and feel bad about it too.
但我确实理解你的心情 我也很难过
It might not exactly make up for it, but I want to give Ai some work.
不太算是替代吧 但我想给爱一些别的工作
It's for a film. No complaints, right?
是一部电影 这下就没有怨言了吧
Seriously?
真的吗？
But…
但是
on the condition that you're cast too.
条件是你也要出演
Listen, Mature Baby.
听着 小大人
In Japan, the casting is usually all decided by the higher-ups already.
在日本 演员的选角 通常是由高层决定好的
The more money goes into the project, the more it has to succeed.
项目投入了很多钱 不允许失败
The higher-ups have their own battle to get actors who can call an audience.
为了获得能吸引观众的演员 高层有他们自己的斗争
The only directors who have casting rights are either super bigshots
拥有选角权的导演 要么是超级大腕
or super low-budget small-scale film directors.
要么是超低成本的小成本电影导演
Now, which one do I look like?
我看起来是哪一种？
A super bigshot--
超级大…
And wrong!
错了
This is a low-budget film set.
这是一个低成本电影的片场
Director, thank you for taking care of Aqua today.
导演 谢谢你今天使用阿夸
No, no. Has that one issue been worked out?
不用 那个问题解决了吗？
I believe so. Aqua belongs to Ichigo Production starting this month.
我想是的 从本月开始 阿夸就签到莓制作公司旗下
People get mad if I use a child who isn't with an agency.
如果我用一个没有经纪公司的孩子 人们会很生气
If it's acting, I'm sure my sister is better than me.
如果是演戏 妹妹肯定比我演得好
No, I want you.
不 我要你
I'm casting Ai in exchange for you.
我用爱来换你
This is called a barter in this industry.
这在这个世界叫做物物交换
This is basic knowledge, so remember it.
这是基础知识 所以记住咯
Your appearance was bartered for Ai to be cast?
爱是被人拿去 换来了儿子的？
That scary director seems to really like you, Aqua.
那个长相可怕的导演 似乎真的很喜欢你 阿夸
What did you do to end up this way?
你到底做了什么？
I didn't do anything special.
我没做什么特别的事
Old-timers like being treated casually by young people for some reason,
出于某种原因 老大爷们总喜欢被年轻人随意对待
so I purposely don't act too polite.
所以我故意表现得不太礼貌
What a snotty baby.
真是个讨厌的小孩
I used to work with grandpas and grandmas, so I know how to deal with my elders.
我以前的工作对象里有很多爷爷奶奶 所以我知道如何和长辈打交道
Who knew this odd skill would come to use?
谁知道这个奇怪的技能会派上用场？
Mama! Mama!
妈妈
I wanna go back to Mama's place! Why isn't Mama here?!
我想回妈妈家 妈妈怎么不在这里？
Ai films on a different day.
爱在不同的日子拍摄电影
I wanna go home and goo-goo! I wanna ga-ga in Mama's chest!
我想回家咕咕 我想嘎嘎妈妈的胸口
Isn't she embarrassed to do that at her age?
她这把年纪了 做这种事难道不尴尬吗？
Not that I know how old she is.
虽然我不知道她多大
This is a place for pros!
这是专业人士待的地方
If you're here to play, go home!
如果你是来玩的 那就回家去吧
Um…
那个…
I'm Kana Arima, this film's actress.
我是有马加奈 这部电影的女主角
Oh, isn't she that one girl?
她不是那个女孩吗？
Um, what was it again?
是什么来着？
The genius child actress who licks baking soda?
那个十分爱舔苏打的天才童星？
who can cry in ten seconds!
是“十秒钟就能哭出来的天才童星”
Everyone says my crying in TV dramas are amazing! I'm amazing!
大家都说我在电视剧里的哭戏太棒了 我太厉害了
I don't really like this kid.
我不太喜欢这孩子
She feels fake, so my gut says I can't stand her.
感觉她很假 所以我的直觉告诉我 我受不了她
Sometimes people are strangely hard on child actors, like you.
有时候人们对童星特别苛刻 比如你
I know that you got in with connections.
我知道你是靠关系进来的
At the script reading stage, you and that idol weren't even in this.
在读剧本的时候 你和那个偶像都不在里面
Mama said the director squeezed them in!
妈妈说导演把他们塞进去了
You know that's a no-no!
你知道这是不行的
No, that's not exactly--
不 不完全是…
I saw the TV drama the director shot before, but that idol was barely in it.
我以前看过导演拍的电视剧 但是那个偶像几乎没有出现
Huh?
什么？
I bet her acting was so bad they had to cut it all out.
我敢打赌 她的演技太烂了 他们不得不全部剪掉
But I guess she's good at kissing up to people.
但她很擅长拍马屁
Assistant Director, hold my bag!
导演助理 拿着我的包
Um, wait just one second.
那个…等一下
Bro…
哥哥
I know. She's just a kid… I won't kill her.
我知道 她只是个孩子 我不会杀她的
To simply sum up the plot of the film…
简单介绍一下这部电影
A woman who is not confident in her appearance
这部电影讲述的是 一个对自己外表没有信心的女人
gets plastic surgery at a sketchy hospital deep in the mountains for some reason.
在深山里一家简陋的医院中 接受整形手术的故事
We are the creepy children that the woman meets at the village entrance.
我们是那个女人 在村口遇到的令人毛骨悚然的孩子
Greetings, visitor. We welcome you.
你好 客人 我们欢迎你
Please make yourself at home.
请不要拘束 自在一些
As expected of a genius child actress. She's good.
真是个天才童星 她演得很好
If I tried doing the same, the difference would be painful to watch.
如果我试着做同样的表演 这种演技上的差异也会让人看不下去
Even a complete amateur can tell that much.
即使是一个完全的业余爱好者 也能看出这一点
Then what do I do?
那我该怎么办？
In normal circumstances, I would just have to act like a creepy child.
最明显的方法 就是扮演一个令人毛骨悚然的孩子
But that's not what's being demanded of me.
但这不是对我的要求
What the director wants is probably…
导演想要的画面一定是…
In this village, there is only one inn.
在这个村子里 只有一家客栈
Once you check in, you may explore the area.
办理入住手续后 你可以到处逛逛
This scene was one that was added later on.
这一幕是突然新增的部分
After learning of me, the director wrote it with me in mind.
导演知道我之后 基于我的样子 写了这部分的剧本
If I consider that fact, I shouldn't have to act.
如果考虑到这个事实 我根本不需要特别去演
Following the stage directions is enough.
遵循表演指导 就足够了
He never said it out loud, but what the director means to say is…
导演从来没用言语表达过 但他其实想说的是…
Even without acting, you're creepy enough.
就算不演戏 你也足够让人毛骨悚然
Now, let me guide you.
现在 我带你去吧
Cut! Good!
停 好
Looks really good!
看起来真的很好
Wasn't that just my usual brother?
哥哥平常不就那样吗？
Wow! You gave me the chills.
太棒了 姐姐我刚才不寒而栗了呢
Really? That's good.
真的吗？太好了
It's not good.
才不好呢
Put that camera away. Let's take the next one.
把摄像机收起来 我们拍下一条
Yes, sir!
是
Director, retake that scene.
导演 重拍那场戏
Hm? Well, there were no problems.
什么？那条没问题啊
There's a big problem!
有个大问题！
My acting…
刚才
was nowhere near as good as that kid.
我比那男孩演得差多了
No! One more time!
不行 再来一次
Please! I'll do it much better this time!
拜托 这次我会演得更好
-One more time! Please! -Kana.
-再来一次 求你了 -加奈
Mature Baby.
小大人
What do you think is most important as an actor?
你认为做演员最重要的是什么？
Hmm. Talent or having a good sense?
天赋或天然有感觉？
Motivation and effort?
动力和努力？
Well, those are important too.
这些也很重要
But in the end, it's communication skills.
最终要的是沟通的能力
If the other actors or staff don't like you, you'll lose work fast.
如果其他演员或工作人员不喜欢你 你很快就会失去工作
There's no future for a bigheaded kid acting like a diva already.
一个自负耍大牌的童星 已经没有未来了
Did you want to teach her a lesson?
你想给她一个教训吗？
I wasn't thinking of anything self-righteous like that.
我没想过那种自以为是的事
But it's good experience.
但这是很好的经验
Your acting was dead on to how I envisioned it.
你的演技完全符合我的想象
That girl was much better.
那个女孩演得好多了
I was just being my usual self.
我只是在做我自己
But I never said a word to do that.
但我从来没说过要那么做
Reading my mind is communication too.
读懂我的心思也是沟通的一部分
Of course, acting upon understanding stage directions is one of the basics.
当然 去理解表演指导 再进行表演 是很基础的部分
But actors who can pick up on those unwritten directions are rare.
但对于这些难以描述的指示 能把握的演员并不多
Because there's always a correct image in the director's mind.
因为在导演的脑海里 总有一个正确的形象
Rather than great acting,
你呀 比起想着呈现伟大的演技
become an actor with perfect acting.
不如想着成为 一位有着完美演技的演员吧
Well, I'm not gonna be an actor.
不…我想我不会成为演员吧
And that was how I got my foot in the door of this industry.
就这样 我踏入了这个行业的大门
He has a stage name already.
他已经有艺名了
Aqua. I've memorized it.
阿夸 我记住了
I won't lose next time.
下次我不会输了
Three years have now passed since we were reborn as Ai's children.
自从我们重生为爱的孩子以来 已经过去三年了
The film shot by the director was somewhat credited,
这位导演拍摄的电影 受到了一定的赞扬
and he was nominated for a Director's Prize.
他获得了导演奖的提名
Looking back, I think my acting was pretty good.
回想起来 我觉得我的演技还不错
But…
但是…
In the end, Ai stole the show in that film.
最终 爱在那部电影中抢尽了风头
I don't know if that triggered it, but her work has increased quite a bit.
不知是不是因那部影片而起 但她的工作增加了很多
If I were to describe Ai now,
如果现在让我来形容爱
she would be the most trending idol at the moment probably.
她可能是目前最热门的偶像
Ai will be 20 soon.
爱马上要20岁了
We're still spending our days in peace without being exposed to the public.
我们仍然平静地度过我们的日子 没有暴露在公众面前
Also…
还有…
GOROU AMEMIYA DOCTOR MISSING
（雨宫吾郎医生失踪）
My body still hasn't been found.
我的尸体还没被找到
You're looking cute today too! Super cute!
是的 你今天看起来很可爱 超级可爱
Well, Mama's cuter above all though.
妈妈最可爱
What's this weird rivalry?
这是什么奇怪的竞争？
We entered kindergarten.
我们进入了幼儿园
By the way, what were you doing before you were reborn?
对了 你重生前是做什么的？
How old are you really?
你到底多大了？
Um.
那个…
If I turn out to be the younger one…
如果我是年纪小的那个…
What? I knew you were just a kid.
什么？我就知道你只是个小孩子
You'll be listening to me from now on, kiddo.
从现在开始 你得听我的 小鬼
Uh, I'm a grown woman!
我是个成熟的女人 你知道吗？
What an insensitive brat to ask a woman her age!
你竟然问女人的年龄 真是个迟钝的孩子
Besides, who cares about my past life?! Stay out of my business!
谁在乎我过去的生活 别管我的事
Well, that's true.
说的也对
It's depressing to think of my past life.
想起我过去的生活 真是令人沮丧
That's how much I like my current life now.
我就是这么喜欢现在的生活
Compared to the days of exhausting work,
相比劳累的工作
a kindergartener can just eat, sleep, and read a book all day. Easy.
幼儿园的孩子 可以整天吃、睡、看书 真容易啊
But I'm surprised she can play all out like that.
但我很惊讶她居然能 那样全力以赴地玩耍
A kindergartener is reading Natsuhiko Kyogoku's tome…
一个幼儿园小朋友 正在阅读京极夏彦的巨著
Everyone, it's dance time!
小朋友们 跳舞时间到了
Your family will come watch you dance soon!
你们的家人和朋友 很快就会来看你们跳舞
So let's do our best to practice!
所以让我们尽最大努力练习吧
Okay!
好的
No, I don't wanna!
不要 我不想跳
Oh, Ruby?!
露比？
Why did you run off?
你为什么跑掉？
Because I can't dance. Or like, I've never danced before.
因为我不会跳舞 或者说我没跳过舞
Huh?
什么？
Were you always cooped up in your room?
你以前总是把自己关在房间里吗？
Kids nowadays…
现在的孩子啊
I was like a shut-in anyway.
反正我本来就像个“家里蹲”
I tried a couple of times, but I couldn't do it.
我试了几次 但我做不到
I doubt I can do anything athletic.
我怀疑我不会运动
I don't know what you've been through, but are you sure about this?
我不知道你经历了什么 但你确定要这样吗？
You have a long life ahead of you.
你还有很长的人生要走
Oh. Are you practicing dancing?
你在练习跳舞吗？
Then Mama will do it with you.
那妈妈跟你一起练吧
I need to practice an old song for our next concert.
我需要为下一场音乐会练习一首老歌
Mama, that part was a bit weird.
妈妈 你的动作有点不对头
Huh?
什么？
Your hand was higher when you danced at Budokan.
你在武道馆跳舞的时候手更高
Hey, did you watch my concert videos?
你看过我演唱会的视频吗？
What a good memory!
你记性真好呀
Of course.
当然了
I watched Mama's concert videos hundreds… No, thousands of times.
我把妈妈演唱会的视频看了几百遍 不 几千遍
I remember all the choreography.
我记得所有的编舞
How did it go again?
又怎么了？
This part was more…
这部分更…
Oh, are you okay?
你还好吗？
Yeah.
还好
The way you move… It's like you're preparing to fall.
你做动作的样子就像准备摔倒一样
Because I was always falling over.
因为我总是摔倒
If I didn't brace myself, I would get hurt.
如果我做好心理准备 我就会受伤
When you're scared of falling, you fall even more.
如果你害怕摔倒 你会摔得更厉害
Just stand more boldly and stick out your chest.
勇敢地站着 挺起胸膛
You'll be fine.
你会没事的
Trust Mama.
相信妈妈
My life was mostly spent in a hospital room.
我以前的人生主要是在病房里度过的
My body was impaired and it never listened to me.
我的身体受到了损害 它从不听我的话
So I always admired her from my bed.
所以我总是在床上欣赏她
Mama's cool moves are all engraved into my brain.
妈妈的惊人动作都刻在我的脑海里
All of that light is burned into my eyes.
所有的光都烙在了我的眼睛里
She's my light.
她是我的光
If I could just move like that…
要是我能像那样动就好了
Move freely like that…
那样自由移动
More!
再来
Move more!
再动
My body!
我的身体！
Oh, it's okay for me to dance!
我也会跳舞
This girl…
这女孩…
So it wasn't just her acting skills.
所以她不仅演技好
Her dancing intuition…
还会跳舞
Plus, she has her mother's good looks.
另外 她还有她母亲的美貌
What a scary thought…
多么可怕的想法
For some reason, I decided to contact the guy I broke up with.
出于某种原因 我决定联系和我分手的那个人
Hey, the kids have gotten pretty big now. Why don't you meet them once?
孩子们现在长大了 你为什么不见他们一面？
No, I'm not talking about getting back together or anything.
不 我不是说复合什么的
It all started when I overheard my kids talking.
这一切都始于 我无意中听到孩子们的谈话
I've been trying not to think about it,
我一直试着不去想
but I wonder who our father is.
但我想知道我们的父亲是谁？
Ugh, just the thought of it makes my heart sink.
一想到这事 我的心就沉了下去
Stupid, you're upset over something like that?
笨蛋 你为这种小事沮丧吗？
It must have been a virgin birth. There was no man in the first place.
妈妈肯定是少女生子啦 男人什么的 从一开始就不存在的
They were coming to a weird conclusion, so I thought this was bad.
他们得出了一个奇怪的结论 所以我认为这很糟糕
Our kids are really smart, so I'm sure they'll understand our situation.
我们的孩子真的很聪明 所以他们会理解我们的处境
Yeah. My new address is…
是的 我的新地址是…
Oh, it's Ai!
是爱
Lemme take a picture!
让我拍张照
You seriously like Ai.
你真的很喜欢爱
Work is going well.
工作进展顺利
I even reached over a million followers.
我有一百多万粉丝了
The world is looking at me.
全世界都在看着我
Jeez, this sake is good!
兄弟 这清酒真好喝
Here's to your new home! Drink up!
为你的新家干杯 喝起来
Wow, it's Mori Izo!
是森伊藏啊
Stop right there.
别喝了
Ai won't be 20 until next week. Wait just a little longer.
爱下周就20岁了 再等几天
Ah, that's right!
没错啊
Hm?
什么？
The drama with Ai as the lead role has a high viewing rate!
爱的电视剧收视率很高
B Komachi has a packed schedule too,
B小町的日程也排得满满的
and next week, we're finally performing at the dome!
下周 我们终于要在巨蛋演出了！
He's in a really good mood.
他的心情真的很好
The CEO's dream is to take his idols that he produced to Tokyo Dome.
总裁的梦想是 把自己培养的偶像带到东京巨蛋
It's also the dream of everyone at the company.
这也是整个公司的梦想
Is the dome that great?
巨蛋有那么好吗？
It's different from other venues.
它与其他场馆不同
You can't even book a slot without going through a broker.
如果不通过中介 甚至订不到演出时档
An experienced staff is required to control a large audience.
要管控现场的大批观众 需要有经验的工作人员
Even the artist goes through a strict screening.
即使是艺人 也要经过严格的筛选
It's a venue that needs a lot of the staff's time and effort.
这是一个需要工作人员 花费大量时间和精力的场所
It's not a place you can buy with money.
这不是用钱就能买到的地方
Only a handful of artists can reach that stage.
只有少数艺人能达到这个阶段
The dome is everyone's dream.
巨蛋是每个人的梦想
Really.
是吗？
If I'm successful, everyone's happy.
如果我成功了 大家都会高兴
That's why I act happy too.
这就是我为什么也表现得很开心
It's an important time right now. Don't cause any scandals!
现在是重要的时刻 不要引起任何丑闻
No matter what, don't try to meet the father or anything.
再说一遍 不要去见孩子的父亲什么的
Of course!
当然
I am a liar.
我是个骗子
Before I even think, I always say what's best at the time.
我总是想都不想 就说出最好听的话
I don't even know what's true and what's a lie anymore.
我都不知道什么是真的 什么是谎言了
Pat me on my head.
拍拍我的头
Hm? There, there.
好的
I was always bad at loving anything.
我总是不擅长爱任何东西
That's why, I never thought someone like me could possibly become an idol.
这就是为什么我从来没有想过 像我这样的人会成为偶像
You said you were recruiting people,
你说你在招人？
but for an idol? Me?
但当偶像？我？
What a laugh.
真是可笑
Right now, we're putting together an idol unit
目前 我们正在把公司里的 中学生模特们
with our agency's middle school models.
组建成一个偶像团体
You can aim for the center role.
你可以成为C位出道的
Not interested.
不感兴趣
But I think you're perfect for the role. Really!
不 我肯定你可以的 我保证
I don't recommend it. Since I'm from a children's home.
我不建议这么做 因为我也来自儿童之家
I lived with my single mom, but she got arrested for theft when I was little.
我和单亲妈妈住在一起 但她在我很小的时候因为盗窃被捕了
So, I was sent to a children's home.
所以 我被送到了儿童之家
But my mom never came back to get me even after she got released.
但我妈出狱后也没回来接我
If I scared him a little, I thought the talent scout would withdraw.
我以为如果我吓到那个星探了 他就会打退堂鼓
It's okay. I preferred being at a children's home over getting abused.
没关系 我宁愿待在儿童之家 也不愿意被虐待
I don't have any memories of loving anybody or being loved.
我没有爱过任何人或被爱过的记忆
Someone like that can't become an idol.
这样的人不可能成为偶像
My idea of an idol was
我心目中的偶像是
an innocent being that would flash smiles and put a smile on everybody.
一个带着微笑 并且能让每个人 都微笑起来的纯真的人
The complete opposite of a liar and misanthrope like me.
完全不是我这样的骗子和厌世者
Someone like me wouldn't be able to love the fans or be loved by them.
像我这样的人不可能爱粉丝 也不可能被他们所爱
I think that's fine.
这有什么不对？
It's not a job meant for normal people anyway.
再说了 这也不是正常人的工作
That background adds to your personality.
这样的背景让你成为独一无二的偶像
B-But, idols all say stuff like, "I love you!"
但偶像都说“我爱你”之类的话
It's a lie if I--
这是谎言 如果我…
It's okay to lie.
可以撒谎啊
Rather, a beautiful lie is exactly what the audience wants.
相反 美丽的谎言才是观众想要的
Lying is a talent too.
说谎也是一种天赋
It's okay, lie all you want!
没关系 随便撒谎
It's okay?
没关系吗？
To say, "I love you," even if it's a lie?
即便是“我爱你” 也可以当谎言说出来吗？
Deep down inside, don't you want to love somebody too?
在内心深处 你难道不想也爱一个人吗？
You just don't know how and you can't find someone to love.
你只是不知道怎么做 而且你找不到人
Just singing and dancing cutely is an expression of your love for the fans.
只要唱歌、跳舞 就能向粉丝们表达你的爱
Once you become an idol, you'll see "I love you" in the lyrics all the time.
如果你成为偶像 “我爱你”就会一直出现在歌词里
And as you keep saying that you love everyone,
当你一直说你爱每个人的时候
maybe that lie will become true.
也许那个谎言就会变成现实
A lie will become true?
谎言会成真吗？
After hearing those words, I decided to become an idol.
听到这些话后 我决定成为偶像
I wanted to love somebody. I wanted someone to love.
我想去爱一个人 我想要有人去爱
If I became an idol, I thought I could love the fans.
如果我成为一个偶像 我想我可以爱粉丝
I wanted to say it from the bottom of my heart,
我想从心底里说出这句话
so I kept spreading my lie saying, "I love you."
所以我不停地散布我的谎言 说着“我爱你”
I thought I could love my kids if I became a mother.
如果我当了母亲 我想我可以爱我的孩子
I still haven't told my kids that I loved them yet.
我还没告诉过我的孩子们 我爱他们
If I said those words and realize that it was a lie…
如果我说了那些话
That's why, I continue to lie today.
这就是我今天继续撒谎的原因
That's why I still believe lies can become true.
相信谎言会成真
Even if someday, I have to pay the price.
即使有一天 我要付出代价
CAN'T WAIT FOR TODAY'S DOME CONCERT!
（等不及今天的巨蛋演唱会了）
Is that the CEO?
是总裁他们吗？
Yes!
来了
Congratulations on your dome concert.
恭喜你得以在巨蛋办演唱会
Are the twins doing well?
双胞胎怎么样了？
Doesn't it hurt?!
不疼吗？
But you hurt me more! It was painful!
但我更疼 太痛苦了
Because you had kids when you're an idol!
因为你当偶像的时候有了孩子
You betrayed your fans, you slut…
你背叛了你的粉丝 你这个贱人
You ignored your fans!
你无视你的粉丝
I bet you were laughing at us behind our backs! You liar!
我敢打赌 你在背后嘲笑我们 你个骗子！
After saying that you loved us!
你还说过爱我们！
It was all a lie!
那全是该死的谎言！
I was always irresponsible to begin with.
我一开始总是不负责任的
I'm not innocent. I'm sly and dirty.
我也不是无辜的 我狡猾又肮脏
I don't know what it means to love someone.
我真的不知道爱一个人意味着什么
So instead,
所以相反
I always told a pretty lie that would make everyone happy.
我总能撒个漂亮的谎 让大家开心
Hoping that one day, those lies will become true.
希望有一天 这些谎言都能成真
I worked hard and did my best to put everything into those lies.
我努力工作 尽我所能 把一切都放进那些谎言里
To me, lies are a form of love.
对我来说 谎言就是爱
I was trying to express love in my own way.
我只是想用自己的方式表达我的爱
I don't know if I was able to really love you all,
我不知道我是否真的能爱你们所有人
but I sang about love while wanting to love you.
但我在想要爱你们的时候 唱起了书写了爱的歌曲
Praying that someday, it will become true.
祈祷有一天 这将成为现实
Even now, I still want to love you.
即使现在 我还是想要爱着你
Quit lying.
别说谎了
I bet you don't even remember me. You just want me to let you go--
你都不记得我了 就因为你想让我…
Ryousuke, right?
凉介 对吧？
You came to my handshake events.
你来参加过我的握手活动
Oh, was I wrong?
我记错了吗？
Sorry, I'm bad at remembering people's names.
对不起 我不擅长记住别人的名字
I was happy when you gave me that star-shaped sand.
你送我星状沙子的时候 我很开心
I still have it displayed in my living room.
我现在还把它放在客厅里
What the hell?
管它呢？
That's not…
那不是…
Just come right away!
马上就来！
Ai! I called an ambulance!
爱 我叫了救护车
Jeez, I let my guard down.
天啊 我放松了警惕
So this is why door chains exist.
所以说门内才要装防盗链的啊
They didn't teach me that at the children's home.
在儿童之家 他们从没教过我这个
Don't speak!
别说话了！
The bleeding…
流血…
It's the abdominal aorta, shit!
是腹主动脉 见鬼
I'm sorry.
对不起
I don't think I'm going to make it.
我觉得我撑不下去了
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Did you get hurt at all, Aqua?
你受伤了吗 阿夸？
No…
没有
I wonder if today's dome concert will be canceled.
不知道今天的巨蛋演唱会会不会取消
I feel bad for everyone.
我为大家感到难过
And just when the film schedule was being finalized too.
导演的电影档期也确定了
Please apologize to the director for me.
请替我向他道歉
Hey, what's wrong?
怎么了？
What's happening over there?
那边发生了什么事？
Don't come, Ruby.
别过来 露比
Tell me!
告诉我！
Ruby?
露比？
Your dancing at the recital was really good.
你在独奏会上的舞跳得很好
I think that you might become an idol yourself one day, Ruby.
我觉得有一天 你也会成为偶像的 露比
A mother-and-daughter performance sounds so fun.
母女表演听起来真有趣
And maybe Aqua might be an actor?
阿夸可能会成为演员？
I wonder what kind of adults you two will become.
不知道你们两个会成为什么样的大人
Oh, I wish I could see you with your backpacks on.
真希望我能看到你们背着书包的样子
And at the school open house,
就像在学校的开放日
I want to hear people say, "Isn't Ruby's mom super young?"
想听到人们说 “露比的妈妈是不是很年轻？”
I wish I could watch you two
真希望能在你们身边
grow up by your side.
看着你们长大
I wasn't a very good mom,
我不是个好妈妈
but I'm glad that I had both of you.
但我很高兴我有你们两个
Um, what else?
还有什么？
Oh, I need to say this…
我有话要说
Ruby.
露比
Aqua.
阿夸
I love you.
我爱你们
Ah, I finally said it.
我终于说出来了
I'm sorry it took me this long to say it.
很抱歉 我花了这么长时间才说出来
I'm so glad.
我很高兴
These words are definitely not a lie.
这些话绝对不是谎言
Ai?
爱？
Ai, from the idol group B Komachi, has been murdered.
偶像团体B小町的爱惨遭杀害
Early morning today, in a condominium in Tokyo,
有报导称 今天清晨 在东京的一间公寓内
there was a report of a man stabbing a woman.
一名男子刺伤了一名女子
When the police arrived, the woman believed to be Ai
当警察赶到时 这名被认为是爱的女子
was stabbed in the abdomen, bleeding on the floor.
腹部被刺中 血流了一地
She was pronounced dead at the hospital.
她在医院救治时不治身亡
The man thought to be the suspect was an enthusiastic fan of hers,
嫌疑男子怀疑是她的狂热粉丝
and he was declared dead after attempting suicide a few hours later.
他在几小时后自杀身亡
According to the police, Ai had just moved into a new home.
据警方称 爱刚刚搬进新家
It is likely there was an accomplice,
由于可能存在同谋 此案将立案侦查
The Tokyo Dome concert scheduled today has announced its cancellation,
原定于今天举行的东京巨蛋演唱会 宣布取消
and a sea of fans before the venue are now filled with sorrow.
会场前的歌迷一片哀痛
AI TO INFINITY ETERNAL FAVE
（爱 永永远远地最爱你）
The shocking news of an idol being murdered by a fan
偶像被粉丝谋杀 嫌疑人自杀的惊人消息
spread in less than an hour.
在不到一个小时内传播开来
The public's response was mostly sympathetic.
公众的反应大多是同情
But as expected,
但不出所料
there were those attention seekers who used the dead as entertainment.
有些人把死者当做娱乐来吸引眼球
While there were many selfish assumptions and slander,
虽然有许多假设和诽谤是自私的
there were those that were close to the truth.
但也有接近事实的
What do you mean by "No surprise," huh?!
“不意外”是什么意思？
If an idol falls in love, it's no surprise she's killed?!
如果一个偶像恋爱了 她被杀也不意外了吗？
That can't be right!
这怎么可能！
You've all been madly in love with idols,
你们都疯狂地爱着偶像
so how could you deny her of her own love?!
你们怎么能否定她自己的爱呢
You're just taking it out on women since you haven't got a girlfriend!
你没有女朋友 就拿女人出气
That's sick! Drop dead!
真恶心 你去死吧
Why is the internet like this?
为什么互联网是这样的？
Mama just died, but all this stuff makes me wanna die too.
妈妈刚去世 但这些东西 让我也想去死
If you're famous, can anything be said about you?
如果你出名了 你还有什么可说的吗？
"Price of fame"?
“成名的代价”？
Quit saying stuff like, "The customer's always right."
不要再说 “客户永远是对的”之类的话了
That's not for you to say!
那不是你该说的
Those are just words that
那些只是受到伤害的人
people that have been hurt say to accept their bitter reality!
为了接受痛苦的现实 而说出的话
Don't use it as an excuse to hurt people!
不要以此为借口伤害别人
Once three days passed, the topic of Ai's death was used up.
三天过去了 爱之死的讨论热度就已经耗尽
After the news of early snowfall causing traffic jams took over,
早期降雪导致交通堵塞的消息传开后
it was never brought up again.
就再也没有人提起过这件事
As if the snow covered up Ai's death.
就好像雪掩盖了爱的死亡
The CEO and his wife had moved us to their family register,
总裁和他的妻子 将我们改到了他们的户口之下
so we were never covered in the main news.
所以我们从来没有被主流媒体发现
Because the suspect was already dead and taking into account my young age,
因为嫌疑犯已经死了 再考虑到我还小
the police interrogation ended quite simply.
警方的审讯简单地结束了
But the counseling for victims continued long.
但对受害者的心理咨询 持续了很长时间
Would you like to really become our children?
你们真的想成为我们的孩子吗？
Of course, your mother can only be Ai.
当然 你们的母亲只能是爱
You don't have to think of me as your mother.
你们不用把我当成母亲
But I think of you two as my own children.
但我把你们俩当成自己的孩子
What do you think?
你们觉得怎么样？
MORI IZO
（森伊藏）
Mama said that I might become an idol one day.
妈妈说 有一天 我可能会成为一个偶像
Aqua, do you think that even I could do it?
阿夸 你觉得我能做到吗？
What's the point?
有什么意义？
If you wanna make money, it'd be faster with a different job.
如果你想赚钱 换个工作会更快
And fans will always be selfish. You'll get bashed if you get a boyfriend.
粉丝总是自私的 如果你有男朋友 你会被人欺负的
Yeah, but still…
是的 但仍然…
Mama was always shining.
妈妈总是闪闪发光
Ruby will probably get over this.
露比可能会熬过去的
For better or for worse, I noticed she has a pure heart after a few years with her.
和她相处几年之后 我发现她很天真
But me…
可是我…
I've already died once anyway.
反正我已经死过一次了
I don't want to live in a world without Ai.
我不想生活在一个没有爱的世界里
That stalker was the same guy who killed me.
那个跟踪狂 和杀我的是同一个人
How was he able to find Ai's hospital?
他是怎么找到爱入住的医院的？
How did he get to our new home?
他是怎么来到我们的新家的？
The killer was just a college student without any skills.
凶手只是个没有任何技术手段的学生
I doubt he could do anything like what a detective does.
我怀疑他并没有侦探的本事
He had an informant.
他有个提供信息的线人
And they must've been close to Ai.
而那个对象肯定和爱很亲密
The only person who knew her hospital was the CEO.
唯一知道她医院的人是总裁
But would he do something like that to his company's star?
但他会对自己公司的明星 做出这样的事吗？
A colleague?
同事？
No, the members of B Komachi were never that close.
不 B小町的成员们从来没那么亲密
And I've never seen Ai with a friend.
我从没见过爱和朋友在一起
It's a known fact that Ai has no relatives.
众所周知 爱没有亲戚
She didn't know how to contact them either.
她不知道怎么联系他们
Then that only leaves…
那就只剩下
our father.
我们的父亲了
She was keeping it a secret even from the CEO,
她甚至对总裁都保守秘密
but from Ai's limited social life, there's a high chance he's in the same industry.
但从爱有限的社交生活来看 他很有可能从事同一行业
Since he and I are related by blood, I can find him by DNA testing his hair.
只要我和他有血缘关系 我就能 从他的头发中 通过基因检测找到他
The culprit who put Ai to such a fate is in the entertainment industry.
导致爱死亡的罪魁祸首是娱乐圈
I can't die yet.
我还不能死
Not until I find him and kill him with my own hands!
直到我找到他 亲手杀了他！
Director.
导演
Oh, Mature Baby.
小大人
Uh…
呃…
My condolences… I don't know what to say.
节哀顺变 我不知道该说什么
Don't worry about that.
别担心
Hm?
什么？
I have a favor to ask you instead.
相反 我想请你帮个忙
What is it?
什么忙？
Do you want to raise me?
你想抚养我吗？
Hey.
喂
How much longer, Ruby?
还要多久 露比？
Jeez, just wait a second, Bro!
再等一下 哥哥
This uniform is cute but difficult to put on.
这套制服很可爱 但是不好穿
But it sure is cute!
但它确实很可爱
Don't make us late on the first day.
别让我们第一天就迟到
Isn't your skirt too short?
你的裙子是不是太短了？
Bro, you've always sounded like an old geezer.
哥 你听起来就像个老古董
Oh yeah!
对了
Mama, we'll be off now.
妈妈 我们要走了
Thus, our prologue came to an end.
我们的序幕就这样结束了
And the curtain rises on a new act.
新的表演拉开帷幕
And…
而且
I begin my tale of vengeance.
我开始了我的复仇故事
Is this recording?
在录了吗？
Okay! I thought it might be nice to make something like this.
好的 我觉得拍这样的东西会很不错
When you're all grown up, I hope we can watch this while drinking together.
等你们都长大了 我希望我们能边喝酒边看这个
I doubt I'd still be an idol at that age though.
真不知道我在那个年纪 还是不是偶像呢？
Oh, by that time, maybe you two will be idols.
到那时 也许你们俩会成为偶像
You are my kids, so it's totally possible!
你们是我的孩子 所以完全有可能
Whatever you end up being,
无论你们最终会成为什么人
please grow up to be strong.
请健健康康地长大
That's my only wish as your mother.
这是我作为你们母亲的唯一愿望